[phone ringing]
-[Aziz] Hello?
-[Jerry] Aziz?
[Aziz] Hi, how are you?
-[Jerry] Are you ready?
-[Aziz] Yeah, let's do it.
[Jerry] I've come up here to Boston
just to do this.
[Aziz] Cool.
I'm parked over on Highway 20
and Southwest.
[Jerry] You're parked?
-Hi!
-[Jerry laughs]
This bus is called "Good Times."
Welcome to Good Times.
Thanks so much for coming down.
[Jerry] I came up.
-[Jerry] How was the show last night?
-[Aziz] It was good. We did two.
[Jerry] So, how are we gonna
get to breakfast?
I mean, we have a bus.
-Can I drive it?
-Sure.
-Let's do it.
[engine starts]
[Jerry] This is a 2012 Prevost X3-45
in silver.
It's 45 feet long
and has a 500-horsepower Volvo engine.
The brochure for the Prevost X3-45
says it has "classic styling."
I don't know what that means.
It's got... I don't know what it's got.
It's got a lot of stuff.
It's just big, man.
This thing is so big and long.
It's ridiculous.
You feel like you're in
a polished silver building
that just got pushed off a cliff.
Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
My guest today is the very
charming Aziz Ansari.
Aziz is a wonderful comedian
and also stars on the NBC show
Parks and Recreation.
Aziz likes to do his road gigs
with a tour bus.
[horn honks]
I'm just gonna go along with that.
Okay. Let's see what I'm gonna do next.
Put the seat belt on.
-Release my air brake.
-[hisses]
Put it in drive.
[beeping]
[engine starts]
Oh, my God.
Come on, Aziz.
-You're amazed.
-It's pretty good.
[Aziz] You ever use a tour bus
when you tour, or you always just fly?
I fly or I drive a bus.
[Jerry] This guy needs
to get out of my way.
-[horn honks]
-[Aziz chuckling]
That guy's got a great story.
"Uh, so, I guess Jerry Seinfeld
drives tour buses now."
[both chuckling]
[Aziz] There's no one like,
"That's Jerry Seinfeld."
They're like, "There's a guy that
really looks like Seinfeld
that drives tour buses in Massachusetts."
[Jerry] The hardest part of driving a bus,
they kept telling me,
is watch out for trees.
[branches scraping]
-See what I mean?
-Where was the tree? I didn't...
-They just come from the sky.
-[Aziz laughing]
[Jerry] I bet if you're a very young bird
your parents would tell that a lot.
"Watch out for trees, son."
[Aziz] Jerry, don't hurt Good Times.
[Jerry] I'm sorry, Ansari.
That's fun to say.
[Aziz] I spent most of my life living
in Bennettsville, South Carolina.
There's nothing going on there.
And how did your parents
just wind up there?
My dad is a gastroenterologist
and there was no other gastroenterologist
in that area.
That's a good way to decide where to go.
"Any other gastroenterologists there?
No. I'll be right over."
-I'm into...
-Let me concentrate on this turn.
Hang on a second.
What does happen with the bus
is people let you go.
[Aziz chuckles]
You're just a giant flying brick.
This has gotta be weird for you.
It's a little strange.
[Jerry] The most important thing
when you're driving a bus is smoothness.
You gotta be so super smooth
with your steering inputs,
your braking, your accelerating.
[Aziz] If that tree was lower,
what would we do right now?
I would swerve wildly and scream, "Tree!"
Now, I'm gonna back this bus
-into there.
-[Aziz] Whoa.
That's gonna be tough.
[Jerry] I mean, come on. Come on, Ansari.
I thought you were joking. I didn't think
you were gonna back it in.
[Jerry] This is one
of the greatest moments
-in the history of comedy, right here.
-[Aziz chuckling]
Pretty good.
Thanks for the ride.
[man shouts indistinctly]
Thank you.
Please, come in.
Welcome to Brody's.
-[Jerry] Coffee?
-[Aziz] Sure.
-Cheers.
To comedy.
The ultimate racket.
I don't know if it's a racket. It's hard.
Racket's a pretty easy thing.
"I had this racket.
You work super hard all the time.
And you had to be incredibly lucky
and incredibly talented.
And then you get some money.
It's a great racket."
I wanna stop lying in restaurants
about how the food is to the waiter.
You know how we always say,
"How is everything?"
"Great." And then the place closes,
and they go,
"I wonder why it closed. Was the food bad?
Nobody said anything."
Isn't that what Yelp is?
Yelp is the anonymous...
You don't have to say it
to someone's face.
It's like the Ku Klux Klan.
[chuckling] That's a little bit of a leap.
That'd be a cool study to see racism
across different cultures.
Oh, my... fantastic.
It would be a weird way
to bring us together.
Know how Indian people
do white people's voices?
-No.
-My mom will say,
"Yeah, we just went to the store, we're
coming home." They're like, "Wash, wash.
We just went to the store, wash, wash."
And so they'll, "Wash, wash."
I don't know why
they need to repeat "wash" so many times.
-"Wash, wash, wash."
-See?
-Doesn't it...
-I've never seen a white person do that.
I guess when an Indian person does English
and does an Indian accent,
it's very clean and crisp, and then
there's not as many "ow" sounds.
And so I guess that's where
the "wash, wash, wash..."
-Oh, I see.
-I guess that's where that comes from.
The round sound's not so crisp.
Indian accent, very crisp.
I love when people do white people.
I never get tired of it.
The one Eddie Murphy does in Delirious
is a different energy
than people usually do.
The usual energy's like, "Oh, um..."
His is like, "Come on, man. [bleeps]!"
Can you explain to me how is it that
Eddie Murphy, in Beverly Hills Cop...
One of the most famous moments
is he's walking in Beverly Hills,
and he sees the two guys
in the crazy leather outfits go by him
and he just stops
and laughs on the street to himself.
And then in his comedy special,
he's wearing that outfit.
-Yeah. Yeah. Isn't that nuts?
-Yeah.
[chuckling]
-So, the school thing, you were not...
-No.
The summer of my freshman year,
I started doing stand-up.
I didn't know what I wanted to do
and I was like,
"I'll go to business school..."
You had to submit a portfolio
or something.
I was like, "I don't wanna to."
Comedians are so lazy about weird things.
Like, being a comedian is very hard.
Louis C.K. told me a similar story.
He wanted to go to NYU film school
but he just couldn't get through
the paperwork.
-Yeah.
I'm the same way,
I'm so lazy about certain things.
-Right...
-Like, I'll tour for weeks on end,
two shows a night.
Then it's like, uh...
-Can't fill out a form.
-Yeah.
Are you lazy?
Or you feel like you're...
Well, I am lazy with...
Like, this morning, I'm thinking,
"I have the underwear,
maybe I should bring the T-shirt with me
to the shoes.
"Which will save me a trip
back to the drawer to get the T-shirt."
I'll think about that.
"Am I gonna wear a sweater?
If I am, I better get it now.
Otherwise, you gotta walk back here."
It's four steps.
You know, when you're walking,
and you realize you're going
the wrong way,
and you turn around to whoever's there.
"Oh, sorry. Wrong way."
'Cause you don't wanna seem crazy,
like a person that's like...
Yeah.
So, you're like, "Oh, God.
I went the wrong way."
Put the finger up. "Okay, I'm..."
-"Not crazy. I left something."
-"I'm not crazy. I made a mistake."
[server] How is everything?
-Good.
[server] All right. Good.
Everything really good?
Oh, I forgot to think what's the truth.
So, if I was really honest, I would say,
the blueberries are weird,
there's too much of some kind of liquid
in the oatmeal,
but really good-sized coffee cup.
Would it be worth it
to bring up that stuff?
No.
I was talking to a friend of mine,
who's a little bit older, who has kids.
He's worried about his kids
doing drugs and having sex.
So, he installed spyware
on the kid's phone
that lets him read all the texts
that the kid sends.
That's tough. I'm not gonna have kids.
I don't wanna have to be reading
some 10-year-old's texts.
Well, to me, it's like being a stalker.
It's like, "I can't even
get my own errands done."
The idea of stalking somebody
and following them on their errands...
I go to the dry cleaner.
I gotta watch them go.
So, that's twice the number of errands
you gotta do in one day,
if you're gonna stalk somebody properly.
[Aziz] I read this book about
communication and technology
and how things have changed.
Young people, especially,
are using communication mediums
like email and text and chatting,
where you have a minute
to gather your thoughts
and figure out what you're gonna say,
and write, and rewrite and edit.
So, that muscle that helps you
have spontaneous conversation
isn't as well-built for them.
If you're texting someone romantically,
asking them out,
one thing people can do is
they don't say anything back.
They just give you silence.
We didn't used to do this in the past.
There was never a scenario where, like,
"It was great meeting you.
We should get together.
Maybe grab a drink?"
That just didn't exist. It's so rude.
You would have to say something.
In the past, you get over it eventually.
Out of sight, out of mind.
But now, there's social media.
Facebook, Twitter, Instagram.
So, people become like detectives
and they start opening up tabs.
Like, "Where is this person?
Let's see her.
We got a photo of breakfast.
She had breakfast. Okay.
All right, I got a photo of a zebra here.
Is she at a zoo or something?
-Can we look at the GPS coordinates?"
-[laughs]
And you're just seeing
everything they're doing.
-Right, everyone's the FBI.
-Yeah.
And you haven't heard anything.
You don't know what's happening.
"Are they busy?"
And then you see them
posting a photo of coffee,
and you're like,
"What the [bleeps]?"
And I've put myself out there.
Just say something back to me.
-And you see their phone.
-Yeah.
"There's my message.
I can see my own message on there."
What was the first bit you did on stage?
I remember one of my first bits
that I really liked.
There was a big gay marriage debate
going on
and this one guy said,
"If your neighbor marries a box turtle,
that doesn't affect your everyday life.
But that doesn't mean it's right."
And so, I heard that and I started
doing jokes about the fact that,
why would he pick a box turtle?
Of all things.
That seems like such a specific reference.
This guy's definitely thought about
[bleeps] a box turtle.
There's no way
that's the first thing you jump to.
Why wouldn't you use dog or cat?
Why go to box turtle?
Yeah. That's a long list
until you get to box turtle.
When I was young, in that frustration of,
"[groans] I need to be in a better place,"
I was doing a comic strip
and Lucien Hold, now passed away,
but was still there...
So, this didn't happen after
he passed away? He was still alive?
-He was still alive.
-I see. Okay.
-Glad you clarified that.
-He was still alive.
Okay.
He was like,
"Keep working on your stuff.
Everything will fall into place."
And it's the most sensible advice.
When I was starting out,
doing open mics,
there'd be dudes who would show up with,
"Just got some headshots."
It's like, "Really? You got headshots?
Why?
You're horrible.
There's no reason.
A picture of your face
is not the problem."
[Jerry]
Have your parents come to see you much?
I always invite them when I do
a big show in New York.
If I'm doing Carnegie Hall or something,
I invite them.
I talk about how they had
an arranged marriage.
My dad said he just met my mom,
then a week later, they got married.
-Wow.
-Yeah. Pretty nuts.
I don't know. Maybe not so nuts.
I kind of agree,
because the more I thought about it,
I was like, "This is viewing marriage
as a different thing."
Early 1900s and stuff, like,
people would marry someone that lived
pretty close to them
and they would know them a bit.
Right, right.
It has become this thing of like,
"I've gotta find my soul mate.
I've gotta find the perfect person
that makes me feel this amazing feeling.
Brings out a light inside of me
that's on all the time."
You know, and that actually seems
pretty crazy. That seems insane.
That you think that person is there,
and that you gotta find that person.
-That's funny.
-That seems like a crazier journey.
How old were your parents
when they moved here?
They would have been early 30s.
-And their language was no problem?
-No, no. They spoke English. Yeah.
-Right.
-Or they would just see white people
and go, "Wash, wash, wash."
[Jerry] What's the dream,
like, in 10 years or 15 years,
that you would like
to have accomplished.
My ultimate dream would be, like,
if I was like 90 years old
and I could just drop in
at the Comedy Cellar and just kill it.
That'd be cooler to me
than any other thing.
-That's great.
-The idea to-- Being like...
a really old guy,
still people, like, giving a [bleeps]
about what I had to say on stage.
-I think that'd be so awesome.
-That's really cool.
That makes me feel good to hear that.
-Oh, my gosh. Wow.
-I can't sing to you.
-[man] We're a big fan. Happy birthday.
-Look at that. Aw!
-[man] You each get a hat.
-Thank you very much. That's fantastic.
All right. Let's get out of here.
So now what?
I'm gonna go back to the hotel,
rest for a little bit.
Think about the show. Do it up. 7:00.
Seven o'clock, sometimes,
is kind of annoying,
'cause it's still daylight outside.
-Yeah.
-It's weird.
Comedy has a vampire aspect to it.
You don't wanna do it in the light.
[both laughing]
-[man] Hey, Jerry!
-[Jerry] Yeah. Hey, how you doing?
[man speaking indistinctly]
[Jerry]
I'm gonna check out this guy's truck.
-Wanna see it?
-[Aziz] Yeah. Let's check it out.
[Jerry] So that's a Kenworth,
and what model is it?
W900.
The W900.
And where is that in the Kenworth line?
-[drivers] Top of the line.
-Top of the line!
And how many years will this run?
-Ten years, 12.
-[Jerry] Ten, 12 years?
-[man] We can put a million miles on it.
-A million?
We could drive it for two days
without stopping for fuel, 24 hours a day.
[Jerry] What a great gig.
Now, that's a racket.
Wow, how long is this?
[driver] 77 feet.
Seventy-seven? That's...
This is only 45.
Can I drive it?
-[driver] Absolutely
-[Jerry] Really?
I've always wanted to pull on this handle.
-Hey. How you doing?
-[driver] Good.
Look at this. Go ahead. Give it a shot.
-[blows horn]
-[Jerry laughing]
[man] You feel confident on how to do it?
I do things without confidence.
Those are my air brakes.
Man, that's a clutch.
[alert beeping]
[Jerry] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
I'm driving an 18-wheeler!
[screaming] See you later!
[blows horn]
Come on!
-How you doing?
-Good. How are you?
-I'm Jerry.
-Tony.
-So you wanna learn how to drive a bus?
-Yeah.
What's the worst thing you ever heard
happening to a guy driving a bus?
Falling asleep. You got driver's blinds.
Now, you don't drive with
the blinds down.
No.
If you're gonna sleep at the wheel,
you might as well put the blinds down.
[blows horn]
-Oh, yeah. I like that one.
-There you go, you like that one.
That's bus-y.
-What's a "dump lock"?
-No. You don't wanna hit that.
So they actually use the word "dump"?
-Yeah.
-Boy, that's inelegant.
[Tony chuckles]
-Couldn't say "waste" or, uh...
-Uh...
I guess there's no point mincing words
when you're on a bus.